dataxu.com 2011-04-26

# DataXu - How We Work - DataXu

## Privacy

DataXu is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI") and is in compliance with the NAI's Self-Regulatory Principles. 

### Overview of DataXu’s Technology

DataXu offers a technology platform for the management of online display campaigns for advertisers. The platform is designed to value and place bids on individual ad impressions, across major ad exchanges and other ad inventory suppliers. We then analyze and report campaign results to clients. 

### Why Do We Collect and Use Information?

Advertising supports free content and experiences we all love on the web. Our goal is to make advertising more effective, because relevant ads are less annoying, and help the services that depend on advertising, because advertisers pay more for effective ads.

### What Types of Information Do We Collect and Use?

We do not collect or use Personally Identifiable Information (PII). We do not collect your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, Social Security Number, credit card information, or anything else that can personally identify you. 

We do not collect Sensitive Consumer Information, such as insurance plan numbers, financial account numbers, or information about medical conditions.

We collect only anonymous, non-Personally Identifiable Information, such as browser type (e.g., Firefox or Internet Explorer), operating system (e.g., Macintosh or Windows), Internet provider (e.g., Verizon or Comcast), IP address, and whether you respond to an ad. We do not collect sensitive data. 

The non-Personally Identifiable Information that we collect via cookies is used for the purpose of targeting ads and measuring the effectiveness of ads on behalf of DataXu's advertisers and to identify the audience most likely to respond to an advertisement. This information also helps DataXu ensure that you don't repeatedly see the same ad. We may also use non-PII data from third parties.

### What Technology Do We Use to Collect Information? 

We use two technologies to collect information, both of which are widely used on the Internet: 

#### Cookies

Cookies are small text files that web sites place in your browser when you visit them or see an ad. When you return to the site or view another ad, a site can access these cookie files. Sites can then determine how often you’ve visited a site or seen an ad. Cookies cannot be used to access any other data on your computer.

#### Pixel Tags

Pixel tags are small images on a web page or other document. Pixel tags allow the operator of the web page or other document, or a third party who serves the pixel tag, to set, read, and modify cookies.

### Opting Out

There are two ways you can opt-out of DataXu ad optimization:

  1. Block all cookies by disabling cookie use in your browser. This may cause some sites to work incorrectly. 
  2. Opt out by setting a cookie which tells the DataXu system to ignore you.

If you change computers or browsers, or use multiple computers or browsers or delete your cookies, you will need to repeat this process for each computer and in each browser.

If you choose to opt out using our opt-out tool, DataXu will add a cookie to your browser identifying it as an opted out browser. This will prevent DataXu's ad optimization system from using any behavioral data associated with your browser for targeted advertising.

As noted above, DataXu is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative. You may also opt out of DataXu and other NAI members on the NAI site. To find out more and/or opt-out of NAI member cookies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

### Data Storage and Security

We retain the non-Personally Identifiable Information collected via our technology for up to one year. After one year, we discard the information.

Even though our information is anonymous, security is important to us. We have implemented reasonable measures to protect the information we collect. No method protecting information is 100% secure, and we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Information Relating to Children

Our products and services are designed for those 13 years of age and older. We do not knowingly collect information from anyone under the age of 13. If we are made aware that we have received such information, or any information in violation of our policy, we will use reasonable efforts to locate and remove that information from our records.

### Disclosures

Some of our web site partners may place their own cookies on your Internet browser outside of our service; however, we have no access to or control over these cookies. 

In the event another company acquires all or most of our assets, all data compiled or owned by us may be among the items transferred in that transaction. In such event, all the data will continue to be governed by this Policy.

We may transmit or share our data with third-party service providers (e.g., data storage and processing facilities) in order for those service providers to perform business functions for us or on our behalf.

We may share, in an aggregated format, the non-Personally Identifiable Information we collect to do business with related third parties, such as our advertising clients.

We may disclose your information to third parties when we reasonably believe we are obligated to do so by law, and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual prohibited activities, including but not limited to, fraud and situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person.

### Data Collection for Our Corporate Site

Our web site (www.dataxu.com) is intended primarily to offer information about DataXu and our services. DataXu uses information from our web site log files to understand how visitors use our site and to recommend future site improvements. If you choose to submit personal information, we may use that information for general marketing purposes and to notify you regarding updates to our products and services. We do not sell, rent, share, or otherwise dispose of the personal information collected on www.dataxu.com to third parties. Once collected, we will store your information for a reasonable time for record keeping purposes. 

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We may revise this Policy at any time. We encourage you to visit this page periodically to review any changes. All updates to our policy are posted on this portion of our web site. To download this policy, select Save from your browser’s menu. 

### Contacting Us

Should you have any questions about this Policy, please contact us:

**E-mail:** [privacy@dataxu.com](mailto:privacy@dataxu.com)  
**Phone:** 857.244.6200  
**Address:** 281 Summer Street Please add 5th Floor Boston, MA 02110
